<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="87755" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Realistic Workplaces And Households" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="This mod updates the number of households and workplaces in buildings by calculating the building dimensions." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
This mod updates the number of households and workplaces in buildings by calculating the building dimensions. It uses several parameters to estimate a realistic number of households or workers for each building. Several of these parameters can be changed in the Mod's menu.

These are the current supported building types:

* Residential Zones
* Commercial Zones
* Industry Zones (Except specialized industries)
* Office Zones
* Mixed Use Zones
* Admin Buildings
* Fire and Police Stations
* Hospital and Medical Clinics
* Post Facilities
* Power Stations
* Schools
* Welfare Office
* Prisons
* Transport and Maintenace Depots
* Garbage Facilities
* Cargo Stations
* Research Facilities
* Transportation Stations and Airports
* Telecom Facilities
* Parks

## Calculations

Different types of buildings will have their capacity calculated differently. In summary, all of them will use the buildings dimensions to estimate the number of floors and the area of each floor. For each type of building it is possible to customize for the number of workers or apartments per area (sq meter). This will be used to calculate the total number of households or workers. There are special considerations, for example, space for stairs, elevators, lobbys (for some cases) will be removed from the usable area. Also, mixed used buildings will only consider the first floor to calculate workers and the rest for households. And for Schools the number of teachers and students will be calculated similary, but also using a teacher to student ratio. These are just a few examples, each building type listed above have their own formula and set of parameters.

## Existing Cities and Updating Settings

When you apply this mod to an existing city or change the settings, there could be buildings where the number of houshold decreases. In these cases, the extra residents will be evicted and you might notice a drop in population in your city.

## Known Issues

* Existing cities that start using this mod might suffer a lack of residential demand and/or buildings that don't get filled with new residents. If this happens, you can increase the limit of the Find Property requests in the 'other' tab. Note that increasing this limit will cause the game to slow down. Once the issue is resolved, the limits can be lowered back.
* Using the "Disable Fewer Households On Luxury High Rises" may cause citizens to be homeless and also contribute to the issue above.
* There is currently an issue with employee calculations for buildings placed with the 'Plop the Growables' mod being very high. Saving and re-loading the game might solve the issue. However, placing buildings through this mod is not recommended.

## Credits

This mod was inspired by the **Realistic Population** from CS1 and from **Realistic Building Occupancy** and **Realistic Density** from CS2. Thank you for to the authors of Realistic Building Occupancy and Realistic Density: Trejak, Mimonsi and 89pleasure. I studied their code and it was very useful to create this mod. I tried to create a mod that joined the best qualities of both of them. Also, because this mod is similar to them, it should not be used with them.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot1.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot2.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot3.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/screenshot34.jpg" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/realistic-workplaces-and-households.1699586/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.9.3" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.2.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<ChangeLog>
* Updated for version 1.2.5f1
* Removed options to alter find property system limits
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ruzbeh0/RealisticWorkplacesAndHouseholds/" />
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.com/channels/1024242828114673724/1273862795020206144" />
	<ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/ruzbeh0" />
	<ExternalLink Type="kofi" Url="https://ko-fi.com/ruzbeh0" />
</Publish>
